Guide to the IBT COVID-19 Response Collection, 2020 IBT0093
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Teamsters Web Archives, Harvested from the web between April 9, 2020 and October 30, 2020; Series 2
  - Osha Inspectors Are Key to Reopening. Their Ranks Are at a 45-Year Low, 03 May 2020; Series 2
    Businesses rely on Osha inspectors for potential reopening but Osha is operating at historically low staffing numbers
  - Safety Alert, 03 May 2020; Series 2
    Announcement wishing members health and safety at the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic
  - Union Meetings, 03 May 2020; Series 2
    Meetings postponed for the month of May except for the Executive Board meeting
  - Update from the President 4/30, 03 May 2020; Series 2
    President writes that 5 members of Local 1120 had tested positive for COVID-19 as of April 30, 2020
  - Retirees & Friends May Meeting Canceled., 03 May 2020; Series 2
    Announcing the cancellation of the May 7th, 2020 Retirees and Friends Meeting due to COVID-19
  - OSHA 10 GES: Our first Zoom class is full., 03 May 2020; Series 2
    Announcement regarding the free Zoom video classes in preparation for teleworking due to COVID-19
  - Emerald Protection Plan, 03 May 2020; Series 2
    Grab and Go food drive during the early stages of quarantine for COVID-19
  - Extensions to the COVID-19 agreements, 03 May 2020; Series 2
    Extensions to the COVID-19 agreements
  - Ferndale School Bus Driver making a difference!, 03 May 2020; Series 2
    Highlighting Ferndale School District Teamster, Brent Richards, for stepping up during COVID-19
  - MassMutual Market Update Session - May 7, 2020, 03 May 2020; Series 2
    MassMutual hosted a virtual education meeting on May 7 to discuss member's investments and retirement savings amidst COVID-19
  - COVID-19 Update, 03 May 2020; Series 2
    Announcement showing Teamster support for its memebers during COVID-19 and including resource links for Local 231
  - Message from the President, 12 July 2020; Series 2
    On July 10, 2020, the president of Local 1120 announces there has not been any new COVID-19 cases reported.
  - Important Unemployment Extension Requirements, 12 July 2020; Series 2
    New State Extension Comes with Stricter Job Search Requirements On May 24, due to the high unemployment rate, Washington entered an 'Extended Benefits' (EB) period. Entended benefits adds up to 13 more weeks of beneftis to qualifying claims.
  - 5 recruits, 6 instructors at El Paso Police Academy test positive for coronavirus, 12 July 2020; Series 2
    The El Paso Municipal Police Officer's Assosication reported to ABC-7 that five of their recruits in the police academy, as well as six training officers there have tested positive for Covid-19. EPPD became aware the outbreak at the academy in early July.
  - SW Washington Works Together Presents a Virtual Town Hall: Resiliency & Mental Health During a Pandemic, 12 July 2020; Series 2
    Announcement for a virtual townhall to help members and their mental health during the COVID-19 pandemic
  - Action Alert: #SenateFAIL Cory Gardner Car Caravan this Wednesday, 12 July 2020; Series 2
    Announcement regarding caravan around Senator Cory Gardner's office in protest of Senator Cory Gardner's decision to go on vacation after failing to take any meaningful action on COVID relief.
  - How the American Worker Got Fleeced, 13 July 2020; Series 2
    "[The pandemic] helps clarify just how much employers have chipped away at the labor rights and bargaining power that came with the New Deal."
  - Essential Workers Deserve Fair Pay Now!, 12 July 2020; Series 2
    Denver Public School district told essential workers that they can't afford to give workers a step increase and a COLA.
  - Colorado Health and Safety workplace protections, 12 July 2020; Series 2
    The bill makes it unlawful for employers in Colorado to retaliate against workers for raising health and safety issues during a pandemic. Also, it allows employees to wear their own PPE.
  - State & Local Face Mask Requirements for Public Places, 12 July 2020; Series 2
    Reminder for travelers to check the state and local requirements for face masks when passing through, since the rules vary. Local 7777.
  - Teamsters call on Bill Gates to Provide PPE to sanitation workers, 21 May 2020; Series 2
    Bulletin explaining the teamster request for Bill Gates to provide PPE to sanitation workers. The Teamsters are launching a digital advertising campaign around its annual shareholder meeting on Friday. The union is asking for members to sign a letter, "Tell Bill Gates: Use your power to keep sanitation workers safe." It represents more than 7,000 Republic Services workers, which is about 20 percent of the company's workforce.
  - Nurses Open Up About Protecting Mental Health, Program Offers Free Online Therapy During Crisis, 21 May 2020; Series 2
    "It is the the start of National Nurses Week, although the trauma experienced by some of them will likely last for some time."
  - Teamsters Honor Nurses, Saying Their Contributions Can't Be Overstated, 21 May 2020; Series 2
    Article recognizing the value of nurses during National Nurses Week in the U.S.
  - Washington Post: Fewer Hours, Less Pay and More Anxiety Greet Returning Workers, 28 July 2020; Series 2
    None
  - COVID-19 News Updates - June 4, 2020, 28 July 2020; Series 2
    none
  - COVID-19 News Updates - June 3, 2020, 28 July 2020; Series 2
  - COVID-19 News Updates - June 2, 2020, 28 July 2020; Series 2
  - Hoffa: Infrastructure Investment Holds Key to Improving Economy, 28 July 2020; Series 2
  - Motion Picture Industry-Wide Labor Management Task Force Issues Return to Work Policies, 28 July 2020; Series 2
  - COVID-19 News Updates - May 29, 2020, 28 July 2020; Series 2
  - Teamsters Hold Food, PPE Distribution for Port Truck Drivers, 28 July 2020; Series 2
  - Teamsters urge treasury Department to Protect Miami Air International, 2020-05-19; Series 2
    Capt. David Bourne, Teamsters Airline Division Director asks U.S. Department of the Treasury to save jobs by approving the company's application for payroll grants under the CARES Act
  - Airline Professionals Association President Tim Jewell On Stimulus Relief for Airlines: Warns Smaller Airlines Need Relief Now, 2020-05-19; Series 2
    Press release asking Secretary Mnuchin and all those involved with the implementation of the aviation stimulus package to expedite the distribution of stimulus funds to the smaller airlines
  - Reporting Deaths or Illness In Flight, 2020-07-28; Series 2
    42 CFR 71.21 requires the pilots of international flights to the United States to report before arrival any deaths or illnesses (as defined in the regulations) among passengers or crew to CDC's quarantine station at or nearest to the airport of arrival. This may be done by a report to ATC or the company using established means for that purpose.
  - Update from Teamsters Airline Division Director Capt. David Bourne, 2020-07-10; Series 2
    Division Director statement regarding a relief bill for aviation workers due to COVID-19
  - Drug and Alcohol Testing During COVID-19, 2020-07-28; Series 2
  - SAFO 20003: COVID-19 Interim Health Guidance for Air Carriers and Crews, 2020-07-28; Series 2
  - Advice for International Traffic, 2020-07-28; Series 2
  - Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) outbreak: Latest Updates, 2020-07-28; Series 2
  - Suspected Communicable Disease: Guide for Cabin Crew, 2020-07-28; Series 2
  - Cancellations or postponements of Meetings and Face masks, 2020-05-19; Series 2
    Various information regarding facemask requirements and not allowing walk-ins for meetings
  - Heroes Act, 2020-09-04; Series 2
    Bulletin urging Congress to include the EPPRA Act in the Heroes Act package instead of the GROW Act, so that pensions remain intact
  - Extension for James R. Hoffa Memorial Scholarship Application, 2020-04-29; Series 2
    The James R Hoffa Memorial scholarship application deadline extended until April 22, 2020 due to the COVID-19 National Emergency
  - Coronavirus Updates, 2020-07-11; Series 2
    List of Coronavirus /COVID-19 updates and resources for disaster assistance, medicaid, and funding
  - To All of Our Members, 2020-05-09; Series 2
    A message from Executive Officer Howard W. Wells stating that Local 676 is closely monitoring the pandemic
  - Port Truck Drivers Take Action, Demand Protections From COVID-19, 2020-05-09; Series 2
  - Teamsters Honor Nurses, Saying Their Contributions Can't Be Overstated, 2020-05-09; Series 2
  - #StrikeForBlackLives in 25 Cities on July 20th ?" 16,000 Meatpackers Got COVID ?" Teachers Strikes Looking More Likely, 2020-05-09; Series 2
  - "COVID-19 Scenarios & Benefits Available", 2020-07-28; Series 2
  - "Covid - 19 Temporary Leave Policy", 2020-05-19; Series 2
    Policy document on temporary leave posted by member Mitchell Vann
  - Coronavirus is Unleashing Righteous Worker Anger and A New Wave of Unionism, 2020-07-28; Series 2
  - Who Should Say When a Workplace Is Safe? The Workers, That's Who, 2020-07-28; Series
    Linked to locals 992, 570, 255, and 888
  - 2020 Special Bulletin - Novel Coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19) - March 19, 2020, 2020-03-19; Series 2
    Press release containing notifications and resources for COVID-19
  - Coronavirus Short-Term Disability Claim, Series 2
    Empty claim form template for those applying for short-term disability due to COVID-19
  - How to Apply for Leave Under the Families First Coronavirus Response Act, 2020-04-30; Series 2
    Links to resources and how to apply for leave due to COVID-19
  - Indiana Unemployment Insurance - FAQ COVID-19, 2020-03-20; Series 2
    FAQ on how to apply for unemployment in the state of Indiana. Effective March 20, 2020
  - Family First Coronavirus Response Act – Emergency Paid Leave Benefits, Series 2
    Information regarding paid family leave and sick time in response to COVID-19
  - Instructions on Making Face Masks, Series 2
    A short instruction manual with infographics on how to make face masks for COVID-19 protection
  - All Meetings Canceled, 2020-07-10; Series 2
    Local 135 holding June meeting through Zoom Video Conferencing and not in person
  - Hoffa Statement on Appointment to Great American Economic Revival Industry Group, 2020-04-15; Series 2
    A message from President James P. Hoffa urging members to protect themselves and stay safe through this pandemic
  - Worker Exposure Risk to COVID-19, 2020-05-05; Series 2
    Exposure pyramid with descriptions of each level of risk
  - Infographic of COVID-19 Exposure Symptoms, 2020-05-05; Series 2
    Infographic illustrating what different sympoms of COVID-19 may look like: Fever, cough, and shortness of breath
  - Stop the Spread of Germs Infographic, 2020-05-05; Series 2
    Inforaphic illustrating how the COVID-19 virus can spread
  - MESSAGE FROM LOCAL 344 SECRETARY-TREASURER BILL CARROLL REGARDING THE CORONAVIRUS (COVID-19), 2020-05-05; Series 2
    Message from Bill Carroll dated March 2020 updating members on next steps regarding COVID-19
  - LO QUE NECESITA SABER SOBRE LA ENFERMEDAD DEL CORONAVIRUS, 2020-05-05; Series 2
    A pamphlet with basic and necessary information regarding the COVID-19 virus
  - OSHA Guidance for COVID-19, 2020-10-01; Series 2
    Infographic classifying worker's exposure levels for COVID-19
  - Interactive map shows what country you can travel to during COVID-19, 2020-07-10; Series 2
    Link to a map. Link not in wayback.
  - United Airlines One Step Closer to Avoiding Pilot Furloughs, 2020-10-01; Series 2
  - Disney COVID-19 Update, 2020-05-05; Series 2
    Details on agreement with Disney regarding the Company's decision to furlough its employees starting April 19 because of the COVID-19 crisis.
  - Flex Plan Members Update, 2020-05-05; Series 2
    As a result of the COVID-19 Pandemic's impact on Flex Plan Participants, the Trustees of the Entertainment Industry Flex Plan have authorized a Special Open Enrollment in the hope of providing some financial relief
  - Teamcare update, 2020-05-05; Series 2
    Board of Trustees of TeamCare has approved an amendment granting up to eight weeks of TeamCare Layoff Coverage at no cost to members who are laid off between March 1, 2020, and December 31, 2020.
  - Teamsters Launch Website for Non-Union Workers During COVID-19 Crisis, 2020-05-21; Series 2
    On International Workers' Day, Teamsters Publish Online Resources for Essential Workers Standing Up and Fighting for Safety on the Job
  - USA: Who was left unemployed by coronavirus? Women, young employees and workers in hospital and hotels were the first to lose their jobs, 2020-05-05; Series 2
  - USA: Unions demand enforceable safety standards as US President Trump orders meat plants to remain open, 2020-05-05; Series 2
  - USDOE IDEA COVID guidance, 22020-05-05; Series 2
  - COVID-19 Resources, 2020-05-05; Series 2
  - 03.20.2020 Letter From Dr. Cooper on Covid 19 Crisis, 2020-05-05; Series 2
  - "NEW YORK STATE EDUCATION DEPT. COVID 19", 2020-05-05; Series 2
  - AFT COVID 19 CBA GUIDELINES 03.21.2020, 2020-05-05; Series 2
  - IBT COVID 19 FLIER, 2020-05-05; Series 2
  - Join in the webinar from the Healthy Schools Coalition on school reopening amidst CO-VID19, 2020-07-10; Series 2
    Bulletin graphic and link to a document addressing safely reopening Phily's schools in fall 2020
  - Schools Closed March 16- To Be Determined, 2020-07-10; Series 2
    Accouncement addressing the COVID-19 crisis and encouraging people to stay home when they are not at work.
  - Giant Hospital Corporation Takes Advantage of Coronavirus to Fight Nurses' Union Drive, 2020-05-09; Series 2
  - Government Invites Employers to Secretly Report "Work Refusal" Due to Coronavirus, 2020-05-09; Series 2
  - Stop throwing us bare bones': US union activism surges amid coronavirus outbreak, 2020-05-09; Series 2
  - "Hazard Pay For Essential Workers UFCW Local 455", 2020-09-02; Series 2
  - Workers turn into amateur sleuths to track virus cases, 2020-09-28; Series 2
  - Verizon Work From Home Agreement, 2020-09-28; Series 2
  - "SEIU Leads #StrikesforBlackLives in 25 Cities", 2020-10-29; Series 2
  - Uber drivers demand to see algorithms, data that determines their working lives, 2020-10-29; Series 2
  - 32BJ union members rally for HEROES Act outside Trump Tower, 2020-10-29; Series 2
  - HEROES Act ?" Part Five in an Iowa AFL-CIO Series: The Role of Unions in the COVID-19 Crisis, 2020-10-29; Series 2
  - "TeamCare Plan Amendment Authorizing Coverage for Employees on Layoff and FAQ - Special Bulletin attachment", 2020-05-09; Series 2
  - "Garbage Collectors on the Front Line of Covid-19, But Without Needed Protection", 2020-05-09; Series 2
    Garbage collectors' calls for more protections aren't being answered
  - El Paso police officer contracts COVID-19 - El Paso Municipal Police Officers' Association, May 9, 2020; Series 2
  - Texas Deputy Dies After Weeks-Long Battle With COVID-19, May 9, 2020; Series 2
  - Emergency Directives Amended, Aimed at Reducing Spread of COVID-19 - El Paso Municipal Police Officers' Association, May 9, 2020; Series 2
  - Covid-19 (Coronavirus) information - Lansing Labor News, May 9, 2020; Series 2
  - Frontline Workers - You Are Not Alone - Southwest Washington Central Labor Council, May 9, 2020; Series 2
  - PPE Information - Teamsters Local 776, May 9, 2020; Series 2
  - 2020 Special Bulletin- TeamCare Plan Amendment Authorizing Coverage for Employees on Layoff & FAQ, May 9, 2020; Series 2
  - A Message From President Hoffa on COVID-19, April 27, 2020; Series 2
    Link to PDF titled "COVID response"
  - Teamsters call for enforceable worker protections, testing following EO requiring meatpacking plants to remain open, May 9, 2020; Series 2
    Apr. 30, 2020 | In response to the executive order issued this week mandating meatpacking plants remain open during the COVID-19 crisis, the Teamsters Union called on the administration and federal, state, and local regulators today to enforce worker protections and increase testing on the job for food supply chain workers.